<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="English">
  
    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Non-medical personnel can treat cardiac arrest with the use of adrenaline or an AutoPulse.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ On fire? You may be closer to a diving suit than the ballast or fire extinguisher.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ If you cannot safely treat a dislocation, a bandage will restore the limb's function.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Analgesia isn't limited to surgical use. Painlessness is a good friend to soldiers.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ The AED will always reset fibrillation regardless of medical skill.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Drugs can still be administered to a patient in a Stasis Bag.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Liquid oxygenite prevents unconsciousness caused by hypoxemia.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Remember to pick up your limb after it is traumatically amputated.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Kidney and liver damage will cause neurotrauma.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ For a full range of diagnosis, remember to check the Health UI, Health Scanner, and Hematology Analyzer.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Multiple symptoms are exclusive to hemotransfusion shock.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ If you have taken too much damage on one limb, it may no longer naturally regenerate.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ You can administer an AutoPulse in the Health UI to immediately equip it on the individual. Wrench on torso will unequip it.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Keep an eye on your visual effects. An early diagnosis can be made based on the situation.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Neck fractures can cause spinal cord injury before becoming visible in the Health UI.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ The AutoPulse is always better than CPR, and their effects do not stack.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Remember not to confuse hypoxemia with hypoxia.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Mannitol only treats neurotrauma if blood pressure is greater than 70% and hypoxemia is less than 30%.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ Bots will not alert you of their afflictions. Check on them often.</loadingscreentip>

    <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ You can use a tweezer through open gunshot or deep tissue wounds, but this will always cause minor traumatic shock.</loadingscreentip>

    <!-- <loadingscreentip>‖color:gui.blue‖Neurotrauma:‖end‖ </loadingscreentip> -->

</infotexts>